[
    {
        "question": "1. What is Blockchain technology?",
        "answer": "The blockchain is an incorruptible digital ledger of economic transactions that can be programmed to record not just financial transactions but virtually everything of value.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. What is Blockchain Wallet and How Does It Work?",
        "answer": "A blockchain wallet is a piece of digital software that stores private and public keys, as well as tracks and records all transactions involving those keys on the blockchain. A blockchain wallet, in theory, does not store cryptocurrency; instead, all records belonging to these keys are stored on the blockchain on which the wallet is hosted.\nBlockchain wallets have public and private keys. A public key and a private key are used in a similar way in blockchain wallets. A public key is similar to an email address in that it can be shared with others. When your wallet is created, a public key is created as well, which you can share with others to obtain funds. The private key is a closely guarded secret. It’s similar to your password in that it shouldn’t be compromised, and you shouldn’t share it.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. What Is Ethereum (ETH)?",
        "answer": "Ethereum is an open-source software platform based on Blockchain technology that enables developers to build and deploy decentralized applications (i.e., applications that are not controlled by a single entity). You may construct a decentralized application in which the participants are the ones who make the decisions.\nExplore our blog on Merkle Trees in Blockchain for secure, fast integrity checks and validation of large datasets.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. What is the difference between Bitcoin blockchain and Ethereum?",
        "answer": "Although bitcoin and ether are both digital currencies, the Ethereum blockchain differs significantly from the Bitcoin Blockchain. Bitcoin was created solely for the purpose of being a digital currency. whereas Ethereum blockchain is a broader version of blockchain technology. And it is a distributed ledger technology that organizations are using to create new services, however, Ethereum is much more stable than bitcoin.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. What are Smart Contracts and how do they work?",
        "answer": "A smart contract is a computer code-based agreement between two individuals. They are stored on a public ledger and cannot be modified because they run on the blockchain. A smart contract’s transactions are handled by the blockchain, which means they can be submitted automatically without the involvement of a third party.\nThe Smart contracts are secure, transparent, third-party-free, autonomous, and accurate.\nLet me use an example to demonstrate how smart contracts work. If Alex decides to sell his home to Bob. Then they would pay a slew of fees to third parties such as real estate agents, banks, attorneys, and others. However, with a smart contract, they can simply write a statement stating that if Bob pays this amount of money, he will be given ownership of the property. Hence, smart contracts can cut down the actual process and give us trustable options for transactions.\nCheck this video on Blockchain Interview Questions And Answers:",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. What Is Cryptocurrency Mining and how Bitcoin mining works?",
        "answer": "The word “crypto mining” refers to the process of obtaining cryptocurrencies by the use of computers to solve cryptographic equations. Validating data blocks and applying transaction records to a public record (ledger) is also a part of this method.\nBitcoin mining is not just the process of putting new bitcoins into circulation, but it is also an important part of the blockchain ledger’s upkeep and growth. It is carried out with the assistance of highly advanced computers that solve extremely difficult computational math problems.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. What is a Blockchain Explorer?",
        "answer": "A Blockchain Explorer is a piece of software that draws data from a blockchain using an API and a blockchain node, then uses a database to organize the data and present it to the user in a searchable format.\nWant to become a certified professional? Check out our Blockchain Course!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. What Is Hashing in Blockchain?",
        "answer": "The process of making an input item of any length represents an output item of a fixed length is referred to as hashing in the blockchain. Take, for example, the use of blockchain in cryptocurrencies, where transactions of varying lengths are run through a given hashing algorithm and all produce a fixed-length performance.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. What are the different types of Blockchain?",
        "answer": "There are four types of blockchains as follows:\nPublic Blockchains\nPrivate Blockchains\nConsortium Blockchains\nHybrid Blockchains.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. What are the benefits of Blockchain Technology?",
        "answer": "Blockchain technology has the following benefits:\nBlockchain technology employs advanced security compared to other networks or record-keeping systems. Prior to being recorded, all transactions must be agreed upon. A transaction is encrypted and connected to the previous transaction after it has been authorized.\nBlockchain offers transparency. As one of the major problems in the new industry is transparency. An organization may use blockchain to create a completely decentralized network that eliminates the need for a centralized authority, increasing the system’s transparency.\nBlockchain helps in reducing costs. Organizations will save a lot of money by using the blockchain instead of paying third-party vendors.\nBlockchain automates time-consuming processes in order to increase performance. With the aid of automation, it also eliminates human errors. As a result, blockchain increases efficiency and speed.\nThe blockchain allows for immediate traceability. It generates an audit trail that records an asset’s provenance at each stage of its journey which prevents fraud.\nLearn more about blockchain in our Blockchain tutorial for beginners.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "11. Name some popular Blockchain Platforms for Blockchain Applications?",
        "answer": "The following is the list of widely-used platforms for blockchain-based applications\nIBM Blockchain\nEOS\nOpenLedger\nCorda\nRipple Blockchain\nEthereum Blockchain\nIOTA\nQuorum\nOpenChain\nHyperledger Sawtooth",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "12. What is the difference between Blockchain and Hyperledger?",
        "answer": "Blockchain is a technology that allows us to build decentralized systems. When we break down blockchain, the “block” refers to information stored in a digital format, while the “chain” refers to the database where that information is stored.\nHyperledger is a type of blockchain platform. It’s a blockchain-based open-source network. These blockchains each have their own storage routines and consensus, as well as smart contracts, identity, and access management.\nSince hyperledger is a product of the blockchain platform, they have a few in common. However, due to hyperledger’s unique features, both are different.\nMostly, blockchain is classified into public and private types. And Hyperledger Blockchain is an example of a private blockchain.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "13. What are some of the popular Cryptocurrencies?",
        "answer": "The most popular Cryptocurrencies are:\nBitcoin(BTC)\nEthereum(ETH)\nRipple(XRP)\nLitecoin(LTC)\nBitcoin Cash(BCH)\nWhat makes Blockchain Architecture so special? To know it go through Blockchain Architecture blog.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "14. What is a ledger? What is the difference between a distributed ledger and a traditional ledger?",
        "answer": "A ledger is a constantly growing file. It maintains a permanent record of all transactions between two parties on the blockchain network.\nA distributed ledger is a database of digital data that is replicated, exchanged, and synchronized across multiple sites in a network.\nDistributed ledgers, unlike traditional ledgers (think banks, governments, and accountants), provide a system of synchronized databases that have an auditable background of information that is accessible to everyone inside the network.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "15. What is a 51% Attack?",
        "answer": "A miner or a group of miners attempting to control more than 50% of a network’s hashing capacity, processing power, or hash rate is known as a 51 percent attack on a blockchain network.\nThe attacker may prevent new transactions from taking place or being verified in this attack. They can also reverse transactions that have already been verified while in charge of the network, resulting in a double-spending problem.\nKnow all about mining and how it is controlled by enrolling in Blockchain Certification in Bangalore.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "16. Compare Blockchain with relational database",
        "answer": "Criteria Blockchain RDBMS\nUnit of data Block Table\nSingle point of failure Does not exist Exists\nCentralized control No Yes\nEditing/deleting data Not possible Possible",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "17. What do you mean by blocks in Blockchain technology?",
        "answer": "In the Blockchain, a block is simply a set of records. The term “blockchain” refers to the process of joining these lists together. For example, if a company has 100 ledger books, the total is known as Blockchain, and each ledger is referred to as a block.\nAlso, read about Nonce in Blockchain.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "18. How does a block is recognized in the Blockchain approach?",
        "answer": "Any block in this online ledger consists primarily of a hash pointer that serves as a connection to the previous block, transaction data, and a time stamp.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "19. Are there any network-specific conditions for using Blockchain technology in an organization?",
        "answer": "No, there isn’t any such restriction on using it. However, under the worried protocols, the network must be a peer-to-peer network. It effectively validates the new block and assists businesses in keeping up with the pace in this area without relying on third-party applications.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "20. Is it possible to modify the data once it is written in a block?",
        "answer": "No, it is not possible to do that. If any customization is needed, the company simply needs to delete the details from all other blocks as well. Data must be treated with extreme caution when using this system for no other reason than this.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "21. What type of records can be kept in Blockchain? Is there any restriction on the same?",
        "answer": "In the Blockchain method, there are no limitations on the number of records that can be held. It is important to remember that record keeping is not limited to these applications.\nThe following are examples of the types of information that can be held on them:\nHealth transaction records\nManaging your identity\nProduction of transactions\nOrganizational events and management tasks\nDocumentation is required.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "22. How Does Blockchain Create Blocks?",
        "answer": "When the block size is reached, the blockchain creates blocks automatically. Since the block is a file, the transactions are saved until the file is complete. They are linked in such a way that the most recent block is connected to the previous one. A hash value is created using a mathematical function to identify a block. It also shows any modifications made to a block.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "23. Can Anyone Remove Blocks from A Blockchain?",
        "answer": "The manner in which blocks are removed from a blockchain is entirely dependent on how they are treated. Manually removing a block is not possible. If it is destroyed, however, the blockchain may attempt to restore the database using other peers.\nThey can be removed after they’ve been checked to reduce the blockchain’s size since they don’t need someone to perform regular operations. It can be re-downloaded if necessary. This process is called pruning.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "24. What is encryption? What is its role in Blockchain?",
        "answer": "Encryption is a technique that is used to keep the data secure.  The data is encoded to some level before being sent out of a network by the sender in this process. Only the receiver will be able to decode it. This approach is useful in Blockchain because it simply adds to the overall protection and validity of blocks, making them more stable.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "25. What exactly do you know about the security of a block?",
        "answer": "Any users on a network cannot customize a block. As a result, it offers a high degree of security. Furthermore, every block is protected by cryptography, which is yet another vote in this case. As a result, there is no need to be concerned about the protection of data in a block.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "26. Why is Blockchain a trusted approach?",
        "answer": "For a variety of purposes, blockchain can be trusted. Because of its open-source existence, the first thing that comes to mind is its compatibility with other business applications. The second factor is its safety. Since it was designed to be used for online transactions, the developers paid particular attention to keeping up with the times in terms of protection. Blockchain will help despite the type of company one owns.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "27. What is Secret Sharing? Does it have any benefit in Blockchain technology?",
        "answer": "It is completely obvious that security is extremely important in digital transactions. In Blockchain technology, secret sharing is a method of dividing secret or personal information into smaller units and sending them to network users. The original knowledge can only be merged with others if a person who has been assigned a share of the secret decides to do so. In Blockchain technology, there are a number of security benefits it can provide.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "28. What are Blockchain Durability and robustness?",
        "answer": "Bitcoin was founded in the year 2008. Since then, there has been no major damage to the Bitcoin network. For nearly 30 years, the internet has proved to be a reliable resource. It’s a track record that bodes well for the future of blockchain technology.\nIn the same way, as the internet has built-in robustness, blockchain technology does as well. The blockchain can’t be managed by any single individual since it stores blocks of information that are similar across its network.  There should be no single failure point in the blockchain.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "29. How does Bitcoin use Blockchain?",
        "answer": "A transaction is a value transfer that is recorded in the blockchain between Bitcoin wallets. Bitcoin wallets store a private key, also known as a seed, which is used to sign transactions and provide mathematical proof that they came from the wallet’s owner.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "30. Is Blockchain an incorruptible ledger?",
        "answer": "Yes, Blockchain is an incorruptible ledger. According to the inventor, the blockchain database cannot be tampered with.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "31. What are blockchain requirements?",
        "answer": "Blockchain is a truly disruptive technology that has the potential to change business networks. So, the requirements for a blockchain is as follows:\nSmart contracts\nLedgers\nCryptography\nConsensus Protocol",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "32. In what order are the blocks linked in the blockchain?",
        "answer": "Each block in the blockchain is always linked in reverse order. To put it another way, blockchain connects each block to the one before it. Hence, blocks are linked in the backward direction.\nThat’s it for the list of top Blockchain questions for beginners. Let’s move to the next section of intermediate Blockchain Technology interview questions.\n\nIntermediate Blockchain Interview Questions",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "33. What are Block Identifiers?",
        "answer": "A blockchain has a unique identifier for each block. The hash value is used to create a unique identifier. As a result, no two block identifiers would be the same. In Blockchain, blocks can be identified by the block header hash and the block height.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "34. Name the common type of ledgers that can be considered by users in Blockchain?",
        "answer": "There are three common types of a ledger that can be considered by users in the blockchain:\nCentralized Network\nDecentralized Network\nDistributed Network",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "35. How is a blockchain ledger different from an ordinary ledger?",
        "answer": "The key distinction between blockchain ledger and ordinary ledger is that Blockchain is a distributed database that can be conveniently decentralized. This method has a much lower risk of error than a traditional ledger.\nAn ordinary ledger is one that is created by hand or by human effort, while the Blockchain automates all of its processes. All you have to do now is set it up properly and according to the instructions.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "36. What is Double Spending? Is it possible to double spend in a Blockchain system?",
        "answer": "It occurs when a single digital token is used several times since the token is typically made up of a digital file that can be easily cloned. It simply causes inflation, and businesses are forced to take a significant loss. One of the main goals of Blockchain technology is to eradicate this method as much as possible.\nBlockchain avoids double-spending by requiring several parties to validate a transaction before it is written to the ledger. It’s no exaggeration to claim that bitcoin’s entire structure of Blockchain, mining, proof of work, complexity, and so on exists to create this history of transactions that is computationally impractical to change.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "37. Explain the significance of blind signature and how it is useful?",
        "answer": "A blind signature is a form of digital signature in which the contents of a message are hidden (blinded) before they’re signed. As with a standard digital signature, the resulting blind signature can be publicly validated against the original, unblinded message.\nBlind signatures are often used in privacy-related protocols where the signer and message author are not the same individual. Cryptographic voting systems and digital cash schemes are two examples.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "38. Can you define what is an off-chain transaction?",
        "answer": "A transaction that takes place outside of the blockchain is known as an off-chain transaction. An on-chain transaction – often referred to as simply “a transaction” – modifies the blockchain and relies on the blockchain to establish its legitimacy, while off-chain transaction records and validates the transaction using other methods.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "39. When it comes to securing the transactions records, How will you handle risk management when it comes to securing the transactions records?",
        "answer": "Risk management is essentially a method of identifying all risks and vulnerabilities to an organization’s financial records. The best thing to do with this strategy is to take the appropriate countermeasures as soon as possible.\nAnother option is to keep a contingency plan in mind. More methods, such as purchasing new risk management tools, may simply be considered based on the importance of knowledge. Data is most at risk from black-hat hackers.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "40. What are the threats to the information you are familiar with?",
        "answer": "In the current situation, there are numerous risks to knowledge. Many hackers have become involved and are introducing new techniques to hack information and servers that hold financial information as a result of the rise in online transactions.\nSoftware attacks, identity theft, data extortion, and sabotage are all major threats. Trojan horses, worms, and other malicious software are also present.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "41. What are the key principles in Blockchain that are helpful in eliminating the security threats that need to be followed?",
        "answer": "To eliminate the security threats, The key Principles that are needed to follow are as follows. All these principles are fundamental and simple to apply. They are helpful in making transaction documents more valuable.\nAuditing\nSecuring applications\nSecuring testing and similar approaches\nDatabase security\nContinuity planning\nDigital workforce training\nTake a deep dive into Hyperledger by enrolling in our Hyperledger Training!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "42. Can you name some of the popular consensus algorithms?",
        "answer": "The most popular consensus algorithms are:\nPBFT (Practical Byzantine Fault Tolerance)\nProof-of-work\nProof-of-stake\nDelegated proof-of-stake\nProof-of-elapsed time",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "43. What Is the Difference Between Proof-Of-Stake (Pos) And Proof-Of-Work (Pow)?",
        "answer": "The two most popular consensus algorithms, PoW, and PoS can be differed by their operation. PoW consumes a lot of resources, while PoS does not. Other significant differences include the need for a lot of computation power in PoW versus none or very little computation power in PoS. When compared to PoW, PoS is both more cost-effective and has a quicker completion time.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "44. Name the steps that are involved in the Blockchain project implementation?",
        "answer": "There is a total of six steps involved in the blockchain project implementation process and they are:\nIdentifying the requirements\nConsideration of screen ideas\nBlockchain project production\nAnalysis of the Security Implementation’s Feasibility\nManaging and overseeing the project",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "45. What is a Public Key?",
        "answer": "The cryptographic algorithm that enables peers in a blockchain to obtain funds in their wallet uses a public key. A pair of keys is created when a public key is connected to a private key. The private-public key pair is used to ensure that the blockchain’s security is maintained. A public key is a string of alphanumeric characters that is unique to a specific node or address.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "46. What is a Private Key?",
        "answer": "A private key is an alphanumeric term that is used to encrypt and decrypt data associated with a public key. In blockchain security, It is also a component of the cryptographic algorithms. The key has been allocated to the key generator and can only be used by him. If he fails to do so, someone can gain access to the wallet’s information or data, as well as the address for which the private key is stored.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "47. What Are the Drawbacks of Blockchain?",
        "answer": "Some disadvantages of Blockchains are listed below.\nSome Blockchain Solutions Use So Much Energy Because Blockchain Isn’t a Distributed Computing System\nIt’s difficult to incorporate and manage complex technologies.\nThere are also problems with scalability.\nData is unchangeable.\nIt can be inefficient at times because network speed and transaction costs fluctuate.\nHuman error has not yet been eradicated.\nNot entirely secure.\nThat will be all in our list of intermediate Blockchain developer interview questions. Let’s move to the next section of advanced questions on Blockchain technology.\n\nAdvanced Blockchain Interview Questions for Experienced",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "48. How Can You Stop Double Spending?",
        "answer": "With the support of the consensus algorithm, the blockchain prevents double-spending. The consensus algorithm verifies the transaction’s authenticity before recording it in the block. As a result, it is checked by several nodes, allowing for double-spending.\nHowever, since more than 50% of the network is owned by one entity, a 51% network attack will make any blockchain vulnerable to double-spending.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "49. What is Transparent and incorruptible in blockchain?",
        "answer": "Every ten minutes, the blockchain network checks in with itself to ensure that it is in a state of consensus. The network, which functions as a self-auditing ecosystem of digital value, reconciles any transaction that occurs in ten-minute intervals. A “block” refers to a collection of these transactions. As a result, two critical properties emerge from this they are:\nTransparency data is embedded in the network as a whole, and it is available by definition. It can’t be tampered with because changing every single unit of data on the blockchain will require a massive amount of computational power to circumvent the entire network.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "50. What Is Consensus Algorithm?",
        "answer": "The method of gaining consensus on a change of data over the system or any distributed network is known as a consensus algorithm. They are widely used in blockchains because they enable the network of unknown nodes to reach consensus on the data that is being stored or shared. Proof-of-Stake (PoS) and Proof-of-Work(PoW) are the most popular consensus algorithms.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "51. What Do You Think About the Future of Blockchain?",
        "answer": "Blockchain has a bright future. It is currently in its development phase, with both technical and adoption advancements. Its applications in almost every industry speak volumes about its future.\nWe will see a big effect on the blockchain, both industrially and in day-to-day life, as more and more investors become interested in blockchain technology. other technologies, including AI, big data, etc., can also be used in conjunction to make it more effective and practical.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "52. What are the Merkle trees?",
        "answer": "The Merkle tree is a fundamental component of blockchain technology. It’s a mathematical data structure made up of hashes of various data blocks that acts as a description of all the transactions in a block. It also enables fast and reliable content verification across a broad dataset. It also aids in the verification of data accuracy and content. Merkle is used for both Bitcoin and Ethereum. Merkle Tree is also known as Hash Tree.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "1) What is Blockchain?",
        "answer": "A Blockchain is a constantly growing ledger(file) that keeps a permanent record of all the transactions that have taken place, in a secure, chronological, and immutable way. It can be used for the secure transfer of money, property, contracts, etc. without requiring a third-party intermediary like bank or government.\nBlockchain is the backbone of the most famous cryptocurrency named Bitcoin. It is a peer to peer electronic cash system and a decentralized network which allows users to make transactions directly without the involvement of third-party to manage the exchange of funds.\nTo know more Click Here...",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "2) What is the difference between Bitcoin blockchain and Ethereum blockchain?",
        "answer": "We can see the basic differences between Bitcoin blockchain and Ethereum blockchain in the below table.\nPoints Bitcoin Blockchain Ethereum Blockchain\nFounder Satoshi Nakamoto Vitalik Buterin\nRelease Date 9 Jan 2008 30 July 2015\nRelease Method Genesis Block Mined Presale\nUsage Digital Currency Smart Contracts\nCryptocurrency Used Bitcoin Ether\nAlgorithm SHA-256 Ethash\nBlocks Time 10 minutes 12-14 seconds\nScalable Not yet Yes",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "3) What are the different types of Blockchains?",
        "answer": "The different types of blockchains which introduce to the world are:\n\nThere are mainly three types of Blockchains introduced to the world.\n1. Public Blockchain\nA Public blockchain is a kind of blockchain which is \"for the people, by the people, and of the people.\" There is no in-charge it means anyone can read, write, and audit the blockchain. It is an open-source, distributed, and decentralizes public ledger so anyone can review anything on a public blockchain. They are considered to be Permissionless blockchain.\n2. Private Blockchain\nA Private blockchain is a private property of an individual or an organization. It is controlled by a single organization that determines who can read it, submit the transaction to it, and who can participate in the consensus process. They are considered to be permissioned blockchain.\n3. Consortium Blockchain or Federated Blockchain\nIn this blockchain, the consensus process is controlled by a pre-selected group, i.e., group of companies or representative individuals. These pre-selected group is coming together and making decisions for the best benefit of the whole network. Such groups are also called consortiums or a federation that's why the name consortium or federated blockchain.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "4) Where is a blockchain stored?",
        "answer": "The blockchain can be either stored as a flat file or as a database.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "5) What are the types of records that are present in the blockchain database?",
        "answer": "There are two types of records in a blockchain database.\nTransactional Records\nBlock Records\nBoth the records can easily be accessed and can integrate with each other without following any complex algorithm.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "6) List the key features of blockchain?",
        "answer": "The essential properties of a blockchain are:\nDecentralized Systems\nDistributed ledger\nSafer & Secure Ecosystem\nFast\nLow Transaction Fees\nFault-Tolerant\nMinting",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "7) How does Blockchain differ from relational databases?",
        "answer": "The blockchain differs from the relational database in the following ways.\nPoints Blockchain Relational Database\nUnit of data Block Table\nFailure None Can happen\nCentralized Control No Yes\nModification in data Not Possible Possible\nSingle Point of Failure Does not exist Exists",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "Some of the popular platforms for developing blockchain are:\nEthereum\nHyperledger Sawtooth\nQuorum\nRipple\nR3 Corda\nQtum\nIOTA\nEOS",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "9) What do you mean by blocks in the blockchain technology?",
        "answer": "A Blockchain consists of a list of records(some or all of the recent transaction). Such records are stored in blocks. Each time a block gets completed, a new block is generated. The block linked with other blocks constitutes a chain of blocks called Blockchain. Each block, after added into the blockchain, will be stored as a permanent database. We cannot delete or reverse any block from the blockchain.\n\nTo know more Click Here...",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "10) Every block of Blockchain consist of what elements?",
        "answer": "Every block must include these three things:\nA hash pointer to the previous block\nTimestamp\nList of transactions",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "11) How does a block is recognized in the Blockchain approach?",
        "answer": "Each block in the blockchain consists of a hash value. The hash value acts as a link to the block which is before it, transaction data and in fact a stamp of time.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "12) How can blocks be identified?",
        "answer": "Blocks can be identified by their block height and block header hash.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "13) Can you modify the data in a block?",
        "answer": "No, it's not possible to modify the data in a block. In case any modification is required, you would have to erase the information from all other associated blocks too.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "14) Can you remove a complete block from a network?",
        "answer": "Yes, it is possible to remove a complete block from a network. There are times when only a specific portion of this online ledger is to be considered. There are default options and filters that can help us do this without making a lot of efforts.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "15) What type of records can be kept in the Blockchain? Is there any restriction on the same?",
        "answer": "No, it is not possible to give restriction for keeping records in the blockchain approach. We can put any type of data on a blockchain such as Bank records, health records, images, Facebook messages, etc.\nSome of the common types of records which can be kept in the blockchain are:\nRecords of medical transactions\nTransaction processing\nIdentity management\nEvents related to organizations,\nManagement activities\nDocumentation",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "16) Which cryptographic algorithm is used in Blockchain?",
        "answer": "Blockchain uses SHA-256 Hashing algorithm. The National Security Agency (NSA) in the USA develop SHA-256 Hashing algorithm.\nTo know more Click Here...",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "17) In what order are the blocks linked in the blockchain?",
        "answer": "Blockchain always links each block in backward order. In other words, blockchain links each block with its previous block.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "18) What are the benefits of blockchain?",
        "answer": "Some of the important benefits of blockchain are:\n\n\nSettlement in real-time: In the financial industry, blockchain can allowing the quicker settlement of trades. It does not take a lengthy process for verification, settlement, and clearance because a single version of agreed-upon data is available between all stack holders.\nCost-saving: Blockchain allows peer-to-peer transactions to be completed without the need for a third party such as a bank which reduced overhead costs for exchanging assets.\nSecurity and Resilience: Blockchain uses very advanced cryptography to make sure that the information which is going to lock inside the blockchain is secure against hacking attacks and fraud. It uses Distributed Ledger Technology where each party holds a copy of the original chain, so the system remains operative, even the large number of other nodes fall.\nImmutability: A blockchain register transactions in chronological order, which mean every transaction happens after the previous one. The chronological order certifies the unalterability of all operations in the blockchain. It means when a new block is added to the chain of ledgers, it cannot be removed or modified.\nUser Pseudonymity: It is a state where the user has a consistent identifier which is not the real name of the user. The real identities are only available to administrators. It allows users to communicate with others in a generally anonymous way. It helps to maintain user privacy and enables free transactions without any security worries. In the blockchain, your pseudonym is the address to which you receive Bitcoin. Every transaction which involves that address is stored permanently in the blockchain. If your address is linked to your identity, every transaction will be linked to you. It is always good to every time use a new address for each transaction to avoid the transactions being linked to a common owner.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "19) What are the Merkle trees? What is its importance in blockchain?",
        "answer": "Merkle tree is a fundamental part of blockchain technology. It is a mathematical data structure composed of hashes of different blocks of data, and which serves as a summary of all the transactions in a block. It also allows for efficient and secure verification of content in a large body of data. It also helps to verify the consistency and content of the data. Both Bitcoin and Ethereum use Merkle Trees structure. Merkle Tree is also known as Hash Tree.\n\nThe Merkle tree plays a vital role in blockchain technology. If someone needs to verify the existence of a specific transaction in a block, then there is no need to download the entire block to verify the transaction in a block. He can only download the chain of block headers. It allows downloading a collection of a branch of the tree which contains this transaction is enough. We check the hashes which are relevant to your transactions. If these hashes check out is correct, then we know that this particular transaction exists in this block.\nTo know more Click Here...",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "20) What is Double Spending? Is it possible to double spend in a Blockchain system?",
        "answer": "Double spending means spending the same money multiple times. In a physical currency, the double-spending problem can never arise. But in digital cash-like bitcoin, the double-spending problem can arise. Hence, in Bitcoin transactions, there is a possibility of being copied and rebroadcasted. It makes it possible that the same bitcoin could be spent twice by its owner. One of the primary aims of Blockchain technology is to eliminate this approach up to the possible extent.\nBlockchain prevents the double-spending problem by implementing a confirmation mechanism from multiple parties before the actual transaction added to the ledger.\nTo know more Click Here...",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "21) What is a ledger? Name the common type of ledgers that can be considered by users in Blockchain?",
        "answer": "A ledger is a file that is constantly growing. It keeps a permanent record of all the transactions that have taken place between two parties on the blockchain network.\nThere are three common types of a ledger that can be considered by users in the blockchain:\nCentralized Network\nDecentralized Network\nDistributed Network",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "22) Why is Blockchain a trusted approach?",
        "answer": "Blockchain is a trusted approach due to the following reasons:\nIt is easily compatible with other business applications due to its open-source nature.\nIt is safe, hacking proof and encrypted.\nThere is no central authority to control it.\nAll participants agreed to how a transaction inserted into the blockchain.\nThe transaction is immutable means once the transaction inserted into the blockchain, we cannot change it.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "23) What is mean by DAO?",
        "answer": "The DAO stands for Decentralized Autonomous Organization. It is an organization that is both autonomous and decentralized. It is represented by rules encoded as a computer program that is transparent, controlled by shareholders, and not influenced by the central government.\nA DAO can be seen as the most complex form of a smart contract. A smart contract is a computer program that autonomously exists on the Internet, but at the same time, it needs people to perform a task that it can't do by itself.\nA DAO's financial transaction record and program rules are maintained on a blockchain. Since DAO runs on a blockchain, and it's running on a distributed network, you can have multiple combinations of different parties exchanging value and reaching agreements. It means that, to a Decentralized Autonomous Organization, it doesn't matter if you are a human being or you're a robot. You can actually have devices communicating with devices, or devices communicating with people, or people communicating with people. To DAO, it makes no difference because as long as it's programmed into the collection of smart contracts, the whole thing can run automatically and immutable.\nTo know more Click Here...",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "24) What do you mean by Coinbase transaction?",
        "answer": "A Coinbase transaction is the first transaction in a block. It is a unique type of bitcoin transaction that can be created by a miner. The miners use it to collect the block reward for their work and any other transaction fees collected by the miner are also sent in this transaction.\nTo know more Click Here...",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "25) What is the difference between blockchain and database?",
        "answer": "The important differences between the blockchain and database are:\n\n\nSN Blockchain Database\n1. Blockchain is Decentralized. Here, no one is an administrator means everyone is an in-charge. The database is centralized. It has administrators who control all the data.\n2. Everyone has rights to read and write. Only authorized people can read and write.\n3. Peer-to-peer architecture. Client-server architecture.\n4. Here, only Append operation is allowed. CRUD(Create, Read, Update, Delete) mechanism is possible.\n5. Historical data of digital records. No records of ownership.\n6. Blockchains are fully confidential. Databases are not fully confidential.\n7. Blockchain is slow because it depends on the hash rate. The database is fast because fewer people administer it.\n8. Blockchain is permissionless. The database is permissioned.\nTo know more Click Here...",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "26) What is Cryptocurrency?",
        "answer": "Cryptocurrency is a digital asset(currencies) which can be used to exchange value between parties. It uses strong cryptography to secure and verify the financial transactions as well as control the creation of new units of that currency. As we know, it is a digital currency, so it doesn't exist physically. Some popular cryptocurrencies are Bitcoin, Litecoin, Z-Cash, Monero, Dash, etc.\nWe know that the government prints the government currencies like fiat currency such as Dollar, Rupees, Yen or Yuan itself. It means there is a centralized institution exists which can create thousands or millions or billions more of that currency. Unlike government currencies like bitcoin, these type of currencies is created by the same mathematical formulas that make the cryptocurrency work. Thus, cryptocurrencies use decentralized control, which works through distributed ledger technology that serves as a public financial transaction database.\nTo know more Click Here...",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "27) What are the limitations of blockchain?",
        "answer": "The major limitations of blockchain are:\nLack of Technical Talent\nToday, there are a lot of developers available who can do a lot of different things in every field. But in the blockchain technology, there are not so many developers available who have specialized expertise in blockchain technology. Hence, the lack of developers is a hindrance to developing anything on the blockchain.\nNetwork Size\nBlockchains require a vast network of users. Therefore it is not much resistant to the wrong action as well as it responds to attacks and grows stronger. The blockchain is a robust network with a widely distributed grid of nodes, which makes it more difficult to reap the full benefit.\nSecurity Flaw\nBitcoin and other blockchains are associated with one considerable security flaw known as a \"51% attack.\" This security flaw refers to a situation when a group of \"miners\" takes control of more than half of the blockchain network's computing power. If the miners somehow acquire sufficient computational power, then there is no centralized authority to prevent them from influencing the entire Bitcoin network. It means the attacker can block new transactions from taking place or being confirmed. They are also able to reverse the transactions that have already validated during that same period. Due to this, they could spend coins twice.\nFor this reason, Bitcoin mining pools are closely monitored by the community who ensure that no one gains such network influence.\nSpeed and cost of transactions\nThe first few years of the existence of blockchain, transactions cost are \"nearly free.\" But as the network grows, it will NOT be the most cost-effective option of transferring money due to rising transaction costs in the network. From the end of 2016, it processes only seven transactions per second, and each transaction costs around 0.20$.\nConsensus Mechanism\nIn the blockchain, we know that a block can be created in every 10 minutes. It is because every transaction made must ensure that every block in the blockchain network must reach a common consensus. Depending on the network size and the number of blocks or nodes involved in a blockchain, the back-and-forth communications involved to attain a consensus can consume a considerable amount of time and resources.\nTo know more Click Here...",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "28) What is a 51% attack?",
        "answer": "The 51% attack on a blockchain network refers to a miner or a group of miners who are trying to control more than 50% of a network's mining power, computing power or hash rate. In this attack, the attacker can block new transactions from taking place or being confirmed. They are also able to reverse transactions that have already confirmed while they were in control of the network, leading to a double-spending problem.\nTo know more Click Here...",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "29) What is encryption? What is its role in Blockchain?",
        "answer": "We know that the security of data is always matters. Encryption is a process of converting information or data into a code to prevent unauthorized access. It helps organizations to keep their data secure(i.e., prevent unauthorized access). In this technique, the data is encoded or changed into an unreadable format up to some extent before it is sent out of a network by the sender. The only receiver can understand how to decode the same.\nIn Blockchain technology, this approach is very useful because it makes the overall security and authenticity of blocks and help to keep them secure.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "30) What is the difference between Proof-of-work and Proof-of-stake?",
        "answer": "The main differences between the Proof of Work and Proof of Stake are:\nProof of Work\nProof of Work(PoW) algorithm is used to confirm the transaction and creates a new block to the chain. In this algorithm, miners compete against each other to complete the transaction on the network. The process of competing against each other is called mining. It defines an expensive computer calculation. In this, a reward is given to the first miner who solves each blocks problem.\nProof of Stake\nIn the case of PoS algorithm, a set of nodes decide to stake their own cryptocurrencies for the transaction validation. They are called 'stakers.' In proof of stake, the creator of a new block is chosen in a deterministic way, depending on its wealth, also defined as stake. It does not give any block reward, so miners take the transaction fees only. Proof-of-Stake can be several thousand times more cost-effective as compared to proof of work.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "31) How does the security of a block works?",
        "answer": "A blockchain is a chain of blocks that contain records of transactions. Block is the most secure part of a blockchain. The record of a blockchain is protected through a cryptographic hash algorithm. Each block is connected with all other blocks before and after it through a distinctive hash pointer which adds more security to the block. If the value within a block is modified, the hash value will also change. This hash is a security identifier which provides a reasonable level of security to the whole blockchain.\nAmbitious hackers also need to know the hash key of the previous block to make changes to the block information. For those ambitious hackers, blockchains are decentralized and distributed across peer-to-peer networks that are continuously updated and keep syncing. Since these records are not contained in a central location, so blockchains don't have a single point of failure and cannot be changed from a single computer.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "32) What is the difference between public and private key?",
        "answer": "The private key is used to encrypt or lock a message or transaction which is sent on the blockchain network. The sender can send a message using the public key of the receiver. On the other hand, the receiver can decrypt the message or the transaction using his private key. By using the private and public key, the communication or transaction is kept safe and tamper-proof.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "33) Name the platforms that are actively developing Blockchain applications?",
        "answer": "Blockchain technology was first used for financial transactions. But nowadays, its scope is increasing and applies in a variety of industries like e-commerce, data management, energy, gaming, e-governance, and many more. There are several commercial and open-source platforms available to provide the framework for creating applications that support a blockchain. Hyperledger and Ethereum are actively improving the blockchain ecosystem by creating advanced cross-industry blockchain technologies.\nHyperledger is an open-source collaboration that provides tools and techniques for developing an enterprise-grade blockchain solution. While Ethereum is an open-source and leading platform designed for developers, organizations, and business to build and deploy blockchain applications.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "34) How does bitcoin use blockchain?",
        "answer": "A transaction is a transfer of value between Bitcoin wallets that gets included in the blockchain. Bitcoin wallets keep a secret piece of data called a private key. The private key is used to sign transactions and provide mathematical proof that they have come from the owner of the wallet.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "35) What is Consensus algorithm?",
        "answer": "The consensus algorithm is the method of gaining consensus on a change of data over the system or distributed network. Consensus algorithms are heavily used in blockchains as they enable the network of unknown nodes to reach consensus on the data that is being stored or shared through the blockchain.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "question": "36) What are the types of consensus algorithms?",
        "answer": "There are many types of consensus algorithms or techniques available. The most popular consensus algorithm is:\nADVERTISEMENT\nProof-of-Work(PoW)\nProof-of-Stake(PoS)\nDelegated Proof-of-Stake(DPoS)\nProof-of-Authority(PoA)\nProof-of-Elapsed Time(PoET)\nByzantine Fault Tolerance",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "blockchain"
    }
]